媽媽
Mom
凱特   你還好吧
Kat   You okay
沒事 我很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
瞧您這濃妝淡抹的
Why are you all dressed up
你啥意思
What do you mean
現在幾點了
What time is it
差不多五點左右
Almost five.
不會吧
Really
我得去準備夜飯了
I need to get dinner started.
我媽媽失蹤那年 我剛17歲
I was 17 when my mother disappeared.
那時我渾渾噩噩 除了荷爾蒙過剩的身體髮膚
Just as I was becoming nothing but my body,flesh and blood,
什麼也沒有
and raging hormones.
而我媽卻已經連軀體也拋棄了
She stepped out of hers and left it behind.
風雪中的白鳥
嗨 希爾曼夫人 菲爾在家嗎
Hi,Mrs. Hillman. Is Phil home
不 不好意思 凱特麗娜 他還沒回來
No. I'm sorry,Katrina. He's... he's not back yet.
真的
Really
說好要來學校接我的
Supposed to pick me up from school.
他一定在路上了 你知道他的為人
I'm sure he's on his way. You know how he is.
呃 進來坐會等等他吧
Uh,w... w... would you like to come in and... and wait for him
不用了 告訴他我來過就行
That's okay. Just tell him that I stopped by.
當然
I will.
謝謝您 希夫人
Thanks,Mrs. Hillman.
喔 不客氣 親愛的
Oh,no problem,dear.
1988年 秋冬
老爸
Dad
你這麼早回家了
What are you doing home already
看到你媽了嗎
Have you seen your mother
沒有 怎麼
No,why
她走了
She's gone.
"她走了"是啥意思
What do you mean she's gone
我回到家 她不在
I came home and she wasn't here.
她可能在買東西什麼的
She's probably at the store or something.
她的車還在車庫
Her car is in the garage.
哦 天啊 別逗了 她會回來的
Oh my God,stop being so melodramatic. She'll turn up.
我給所有人都打過電話 但沒人說見過她
I called everyone. Nobody's seen her.
爸 別擔心啦 我相信一切都會好好的
Dad,don't worry. I'm sure everything's fine.
嗯
Yeah.
我回房去了
I'm going to my room.
是啊 太離譜了 媽媽連個字條都沒留
Yeah,it was weird. She didn't leave a note or anything.
爸爸卻已經心煩意亂了
And dad is totally freaking out.
你覺得她會去哪
Where do you think she is
也許她最終選擇離開他
Maybe she finally left him.
被威懾了那麼多年
She's been threatening to for all these years.
那 她有沒有什麼 古怪的行為
Well,was she,like,acting weird or something
絲毫沒有
No weirder than usual.
對了 你倒提醒我了 上禮拜我放學回家
Actually,no. Last week I came home from school
看見她睡在我的床上
and I found her sleeping in my bed.
啥
What
對啊 很隨便 對吧
Yeah. Random,Right
她醒來的時候 貌似有點
When she woke up,she seemed like,
迷迷糊糊
all confused and out of it.
我覺得她還在半睡半醒之間
I think she was still half in a dream.
好了 說說你 你今天去哪了
So,anyways,where the hell were you today
哦 對
Oh,yeah.
對不起 我 我在托馬斯商場逛了很久 之後
Sorry,I... I was hanging out at Thomas',and...
之後你嗑藥了
And you were stoned.
呃 算是吧
Uh,maybe.
要我來你那嗎
You want me to come over
我不知道 我有好多作業要做呢
I don't know,I kind of have a lot of homework to do.
啥時候你開始關心什麼狗屁作業了
Since when do you give a shit about homework
我媽媽開始關心起我的成績來了
My mom's been on my case lately about my grades.
菲爾 我們有多久沒搞了 一個多禮拜了吧
Phil,we haven't had sex in,like,over a week.
我好想愛愛
I miss fucking you.
我也一樣 寶貝 但老話說的好
Same here,babe. But,you know what they say.
"小別勝新婚"
Absence makes the heart get stronger.
是啊
Yeah.
菲爾 還沒睡吧
Phil,are you in there
我在打電話
I'm on the phone.
你能出來一會嗎 兒子
Could you come out here for a minute,honey
我聽到外面有古怪的聲音
I heard a strange noise outside.
你總是各種幻聽
You're always hearing strange noises.
行 我一會就來
Yeah,I'll be out in a sec.
我要掛了 我的瘋媽又在胡思亂想了
I gotta go. My crazy mom is imagining things again.
嗯嗯 回聊
Hmm okay. Talk to you later.
拜拜
Okay.
還是沒消息
So,no word
你覺得我們應該報警嗎
You think we should call the police
我不想搞的左右鄰居都來圍觀
I don't want them coming here for all the neighbors to see.
你媽媽也不喜歡這樣
Your mother wouldn't like it.
如果到明早還沒有音訊
If we don't hear anything by morning,
我們去電台登個尋人啟事
let's take a drive down to the station.
媽媽
Mom
媽媽 你怎麼了
Mom,what happened
當我還是小孩子時 我媽媽想給我
When I was little,my mother tried...
做一頭卷髮
to curl my hair.
哦 好吧 反正也嘗試過了
Oh,well. We tried.
瞅著有點太飄柔了 我想
It looks a little fuller,I suppose.
她給我起名叫凱特麗娜 這樣她就可以叫我凱特
She named me Katrina so that she could call me Kat,
因為她一直想要個寵物
because she always wanted a pet.
來 凱特 學貓叫 來 小貓咪 叫幾聲
Come here,Kat. Purr for me,kitty. Come on. Purr.
喵 喵 喵
Purr. Purr. Purr.
太棒了 真乖 真是聽話的小貓咪
That's it. Good,good little kitty.
多年啦 我都覺得自己是她的寵物貓
For years I thought I was her pet.
凱特 凱特
Kat Kat
媽媽
Mama
我在這兒 凱特 在這兒
I'm here,Kat. I'm here.
不許再吃了 天啊 你都肥成什麼樣了
No more for you. God,you're getting fatter by the hour.
媽媽想讓我長成窈窕淑女
My mother always wanted me to be a sylph,
如她一樣輕盈優雅
all lithe and elegant like her.
當我步入青春 我的身體與日俱變
And when I hit puberty,my body changed seemingly overnight,
身材如同陽光下的雪人一樣蛻變
the bulk melting off like I was a snowman in the sun.
只是 沒有讓她開心
Only,instead of finally pleasing her,
反而被她嫌棄了
that somehow made her resent me even more.
你喜歡那男孩嗎   天啊 你嚇死我了
Do you love the boy   God,Jesus,you scared me.
你啥時候進來的
How long have you been standing there
抱歉 我不是想嚇你
Sorry,I didn't mean to startle you.
該回答我的問題了吧
Well,are you going to answer my question
啥問題
What question
隔壁的男孩 你愛上他了
That boy next door. Do you love him
你在說什麼啊 不關你的事
What are you talking about It's none of your business.
我不愛你的父親
I don't love your father.
事實上我對他無法忍受
I can't stand him,as a matter of fact.
搞什麼 跟我說這些
What the fuck Why would you say that to me
滾出去跟別人說去
Go fuckin' tell it to someone else.
沒有留字條
So no note,huh
沒 什麼都沒有
No. Nothing.
你說她連包都沒背
You say she didn't pack a bag.
就我目前所知 家裏什麼也沒丟
Well,nothing seems to be missing as far as I can tell.
這警官是那種和我爸 菲爾 都截然不同的男人
The detective was the polar opposite of men like my father,and Phil.
他是攜槍上陣的人
He was the kind of man who carried a gun,got into fights,
神擋殺神 佛擋殺佛
killed things with his bare hands.
她是否抑鬱
Was she depressed
有沒有服藥或接受治療呢 有沒有別的
Was she on any kind of medication,or taking anything
我媽她不會自殺的
She didn't kill herself,
如果你是想暗示什麼的話
if that's what you're trying to imply.
嗯 好消息是
Well,the good news is that,
目前本市所有醫院和殯儀館暫無匹配
there's no matches at any of the hospitals or morgue.
也沒有暴力犯罪的證據
No evidence of foul play.
然而 我最不想說的是
However,and I hate to be the one to tell you this,
每周有上百名人妻走失
hundreds of wives go missing every week.
老兄 如果一個女人想人間蒸發 她是可以做到的
If a woman wants to vanish,buddy,she can.
你是說我們無能為力了
Are you saying there's nothing we can do
哦 對
Oh,sure there is.
我建議你提醒下朋友與鄰居
I recommend you alert your friends,your neighbors.
讓他們隨時張望注意
Tell them to be on the lookout.
留心你的銀行賬戶 你信用卡的
Keep an eye on your bank account,your credit cards,
任何使用記錄
for any kind of activity.
家裏有錄音電話嗎
Got an answering machine
很好 開著就行 你妻子可能會試圖聯繫你
Good,keep it on. Your wife might try to contact you.
如果有轉機 空閒時通知我一聲
Feel free to call me if anything comes up.
老爸
Dad
你媽媽從沒有愛過我
Your mother never loved me.
我不知道該說什麼 因為我記不起媽媽
I didn't know what to say,because I couldn't remember
曾以哪怕輕蔑的眼神看著爸爸
my mother ever looking at my dad with anything but contempt.
也許很久很久之前
Maybe a zillion eons ago
當他們還年輕時 事情會大不相同了
when they were young,it was different.
超贊 對吧
It's perfect,right
這正是我想要的一切
It's everything I've ever wanted.
她高挑 靚麗
She was tall,stunning,
如同電影明星
like a movie star.
他們是典型的美國好夫妻
They were the quintessential American couple,
未來如綿延無盡的魔毯在他們面前鋪開
the future unfurling before them like some endless magic carpet.
如果做家務是一門藝術或科學
If homemaking was an art or science,
我媽可以拿到諾貝爾獎
my mother would have won a Nobel Prize.
但是 一旦房子完美無瑕
But once the house is immaculate,
一切就緒
and everything was in its place,
她就碌碌無為
she had nothing left to do
空虛度日
but plan the emptiness of days to come.
歲月如梭 曾經的美婦逐漸
And gradually,the beautiful woman she once was
淪落為一個暴風雪中徘徊的幽靈
became no more than a phantom,wandering away in a snowstorm.
你好 親愛的 晚飯吃什麼
Hello,sweetheart. What's for dinner
墨西哥雞肉卷   哇哦 流口水啊
Meatloaf.   Oh,yum.
你做的肉卷是最好吃的
Your meatloaf is the cat's meow.
對了 還記得我在辦公室抽獎活動上買的刮刮卡嗎
So anyway,Do you remember that ticket I bought at the office raffle
我好像忘了   猜猜怎麼著 我刮中了
Not really.   Well,guess what I won.
刮了個燉鍋   咱家用不著燉鍋
It's a crock pot.   We don't need a crock pot.
什麼玩意兒用不著啊
What are you talking about
這可是最新產品 人手一個的
These are the latest thing. Everyone's getting one.
你可以燉川味螞蟻上樹 水煮肉片什麼的
You can make,uh,stews,pot roast,chili.
哦 我沒時間講究這些
Well,I don't have time to fuss with it now.
我要做飯了
I have to finish dinner.
先放著吧 放冰箱上面就行
Just put it out of the way. Over there,on top of the fridge.
他是受氣包
He was her doormat.
可他又放任媽媽衝他撒野
She treated him like shit and he let her.
你可以想像一下 當我看到工作時的父親的那種震驚程度
So imagine my shock when I visited my father
他在職場如魚得水
at work one day and discovered he had game.
每個女人都在和他調情
Every woman there was into him.
眉來眼去 暗送秋波
Flirting with him,batting their eyelashes.
早上好 康納斯先生 這位美麗的小姐是誰呀
Good morning,Mr. Connors. And who is this pretty young lady
早上好 敏蒂 這是凱特 新來的前台
Good morning,Mindy. This is Kat,the new receptionist.
我震驚了
I was stunned.
這些女人都覺得我老爸非常性感迷人
These women actually thought my dad was hot.
但在我老媽眼裏 他卻是苦逼的象徵
But to my mother,he would always be pathetic.
就像口生物鐘
A constant reminder of
時刻提醒她忍受那難以忍受的重複生活
the unbearable repetition
以及生命中的乏味無趣
and dullness of her life.
兩人的婚姻如同冰泉上
My parents' marriage was like a long drink of water
長久飲啜
from a frozen fountain.
冰冷入骨 讓你牙齒也冷到透明
So cold it turns your teeth to diamonds.
知道他們的性生活糟糕透頂 也毫不為奇
It was hardly a surprise to learn their sex life sucked.
同時 爸爸還有自己的私密抽屜
Meanwhile,My father had his own drawer of secrets.
他們就這樣過日子
So they just went on like that.
我媽媽從不動情 爸爸在地下室擼管
My mom never coming,my dad jacking off in the basement,
所有的一切偽裝成美好
all the while pretending everything was fine.
這就是他媽的美好人生中
That we were the perfect family
他媽的美好家庭
living this perfect fucking life.
黃油遞給我一下
Pass the butter.
謝謝
Thank you.
好幾次我覺得她都要瘋了
There were times when I thought she was going mad,
感覺她簡直是要用枕頭先把老爸捂死
that she was going to suffocate my father one night with a pillow,
然後像個神經病一樣放火燒咱家房子
that she was going to burn the fucking house down.
但事實相反 她消失了
But instead,she vanished.
你對此有何感受
How does that make you feel
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道
You don't know
你想念她嗎   不 一點也不
Do you miss her   No. Not really.
爸爸讓我去見心理醫生 因為他認為
My dad made me see a shrink because he thought
媽媽失蹤後 我要處理好對母親的情感
I needed to process my feelings about my mother leaving.
但問題是 我壓根沒有情感
Thing is,I didn't have any feelings.
泰勒醫生讓我感覺
Dr. Thaler reminds me of
她就像一個扮演心理醫生的女演員
an actress playing a therapist.
而當我們會面時 我感覺我也成了演員 在扮演自己
And when we have a session,I feel like an actress playing myself.
我 我 之後不久我做過很多奇特的夢
I,I act... I have been having kind of weird dreams lately.
一個蹩腳演員 展現蹩腳的演技
A bad actress. Doing a shitty job.
夢裏面 我開車 穿過凌烈的暴風雪
Like,I'm,um,I'm driving through this gnarly snow storm
什麼也看不見 到處都是飄花
and I can't see anything,I mean,there's snow everywhere.
不知打哪兒來 景象就顯現了
And then out of nowhere,this figure appears.
我無法描述它的細節
I can't,like,make it out in any detail or anything,
但我知道 那就是我的媽媽
but I just somehow know that it's my mother.
我試圖掉頭 但我感到汽車撞到了什麼
And I try to swerve,but I can feel the car hit something.
我走出車門 四下望去
I get out,and I look all around
可外面沒有人也沒有東西
but there's no body,nothing.
只有大雪和刺眼的白色
Just snow and blinding whiteness everywhere.
自從媽媽離開後 我一直在做這種夢
I... I've been having these dreams ever since my mom left.
這不尋常
That's not unusual,
特別是考慮到你目前情況的創傷
especially given the trauma of your situation.
然而 根據主流理論
However,contrary to popular belief,
夢並不一定要暗指什麼
dreams don't necessarily mean anything.
人人都做奇怪的夢
We all have strange dreams.
但大多數情況下 只是大腦的一種功能
But in most cases,it's just your brain's way
在一天結束時散發思維
of letting off steam at the end of the day.
喔
Oh.
我很擔心你 凱特
I'm worried about you,Kat.
什麼意思
What do you mean
你一個人要處理的問題太多了
This is too much to deal with on your own.
你看的那個心理醫生有什麼幫助嗎
Is that shrink you're seeing helping any
我想 只有幾次吧
I guess. I've only been a couple of times.
嗯 我媽說過
Yeah,well,my mom said
我爸走後 浴療對她幫助很大
therapy helped her a lot after my dad left.
但我始終不能理解 她會對你做出這種事情來
I still don't understand how she could do this to you.
我猜她想離家出走   那不是理由
She wanted out,I guess.   So That's no excuse.
至少我爸離開時還跟我們說了
Least my dad told us he was leaving.
而不是把我們留在夜色之中 獨自彷徨
He didn't just leave us in the dark,wondering.
隨他去吧 我們可不可以少說話多做愛
Whatever. Can we just stop talking and fuck
我媽崩潰前我得回去
Gotta get back before my mom freaks out.
再說你爸不是要回來了嗎
Plus isn't your dad coming home soon
不 一小時內不會
No,not for at least an hour.
嗯 好吧 我最怕他把我倆捉姦在床
Yeah,well,last thing I want is for him to catch us again.
上次他那麼惱火 簡直就像要宰了我
Last time he got so mad I thought he was gonna kill me.
至少 給你的心理醫生一次機會 好嗎
Just,give your shrink a chance,will you
好吧
All right.
說真的 你得釋放一點怒火
Seriously. You need to let some of your anger out.
不然你就崩潰了 像你媽那樣
You're gonna crack. Just like your mom.
就像一個惡性循環
It's like a vicious circus.
晚點再來接你
Catch you later.
我並不是想聳人聽聞
I don't mean to sound crass,
但再不做愛 我就要爆炸了
but if I don't get some dick soon I'm going to explode.
加入性愛俱樂部吧 妹子
Join the fucking club,sister.
看看光明的一面 至少做愛是真槍實彈
Look on the bright side. At least you've had real sex.
我超恐艾滋
I'm so paranoid about AIDS
咱們可以並肩作戰
I have to live vicariously through you.
好吧 可問題是一旦你床上實戰了
Okay,well,the problem is that once you've had real sex,
你就會日煩夜煩 朝思暮想
it's,like,all you can ever think about.
菲爾幾乎再沒有碰過我
And Phil barely even touches me anymore.
只有說晚安時那種淺吻
He,like,gives me goodnight peck and that's it.
啥 那也太沒趣了
What That's fucked up.
我知道 我倆就像上了年紀的老夫老妻
I know. It's,like,we're some old married couple.
也許你可以去勾搭那個火辣的警官
Maybe you should bang that hot detective you're so into.
啥 胡說八道 他都40了
What What are you talking about He's,like,40.
他搞我這未成年可是犯法的
That's not even legal I don't think.
凱特 他是個條子 只有條子才知道
Kat,he's a cop. if anyone knows how to do shit
如何瞞天過海 他可以
without getting caught,he does.
是啊 再說了 幾周後你就滿18歲了
Yeah,plus you'll be 18 in a few weeks anyway.
好吧 不管怎麼說
Okay,whatever.
我可不想勾搭一個40歲的老條子
I am not screwing a 40 year old cop.
行嗎 還是言歸正傳 幫我想想
Okay Back to the problem at hand,
怎麼讓菲爾來和我上床
getting Phil to fuck me.
這個嘛 你和他溝通過嗎
Well,have you talked to him about it
試過 他總說什麼自己有負罪感啦
I tried. All he says is that,uh,he's got a lot on his mind,
讓我放他一馬饒了他啦
and that I need to cut him some slacks.
我的天啊 真他娘的白癡
Oh my God,what a fucking moron
我知道 我知道 菲爾在這方面是個白癡
I know. I know Phil's not the brightest crayon in the box.
本世紀最保守的男人
That is the understatement of the century.
這正是我喜歡他的原因 懂嗎
That's what I kind of like about him,you know
簡單 純一
It's just simple.
說出來不怕你們笑話
I know that sounds perverse,
他是像我爸爸的那一類人
but he's kind of like my dad in that way.
如果你願意
You can scratch the surface
可以像洋蔥一樣一層一層地剝開他的心
and there's just more surface.
我搞到了偉哥
I'm gonna get straight Cs
給我看
Show me.
天啊 你真是太瘋狂了
My God,you're so fuckin' crazy
菲爾就是我前文說的隔壁男孩
Phil is literally the boy next door.
但他和他媽去年搬進來時
And when he and his mother moved in last year,
我直接很鄙視他
I instantly despised him.
他遲鈍而又傻缺
He was so dull and stupid.
我取笑他 給他起了個響亮的外號 垃圾仔
I made fun of him. Even earned a special nickname: Garbage.
但那年夏夜 一切都變了
But then,one night that summer,everything changed.
我 貝絲和米奇
Me,Beth and Mickey,
我們每週三都做那些事
We were doing what we did every Wednesday.
比以往感覺更乏味了
And even more bored than usual.
有時候我真希望 有人能把這地方燒成平地
Sometimes I wish someone would burn this place to the ground
那樣我們就不用再來了
so we didn't have to come here anymore.
可不是嘛
Oh,tell me about it.
每周都是這群同樣的爛人
Every week it's the same fucking people
放著同樣的爛歌
with the same fucking songs
還他媽的順序播放
in the exact same fucking order.
哦 天啊   怎麼拉
Oh my God.   What
看看誰來了
Look what the bats dragged in.
垃圾仔來這兒做什麼
What the hell is Garbage doing here
哦 見鬼 他過來了
Oh,shit,he's coming over here.
真他媽是個怪胎
What a fucking freak.
夥計們 矜持點 別吵
Guys,be cool. Come on.
嘿   嘿
Hey.   Hey.
你住在我街的對面
You live across the street from me.
嗯
Mm hm.
我叫菲爾
I'm Phil.
我是凱特
I'm Kat.
這是 呃 貝絲和米奇
This is,uh,Beth and Mickey.
嘿
Hey.
這兒看起來超酷
This place seems cool.
嗯
Mm hm.
你經常來嗎
You come here a lot
偶爾吧
Sometimes.
你第一次來這
Is this your first time here
嗯
Uh huh.
我喜歡這首歌
I love this song.
我也是
Me too.
嘿 去跳舞吧
Hey,do you wanna dance
好啊
Sure.
等等 你爸媽回家了怎麼辦
Wait,what if your parents come home
我媽今天去買東西了 我爸在上班
It's my mom's shopping day and my dad's at work.
確定嗎
You sure
確定
Yeah.
哇 對不起 呵呵
Ow. Sorry. Oops.
沒事了
Okay.
你沒事吧
You okay
嗯 啊
Yeah. Okay.
哦 天啊
Oh,God.
就這樣 眨眼工夫 我的童貞沒了
And like that,in a blink,my virginity disappeared.
和老媽一樣
Just like my mother.
等等 來了
Hold on. I'm coming.
下午好 希爾曼夫人
Good afternoon,Mrs. Hillman.
我是隔壁的伊芙·康納斯
It's Eve Connors,from next door.
噢 你好
Oh. Hello.
有時間嗎 我可以進來嗎
Do you have a moment May I come in
可以 當然 出什麼事了嗎
Yes,of... of course. ls... is everything all right
沒啥事
Everything's fine.
我就是想跟您隨便聊聊
I just thought we should have a little chat.
請進 隨便坐
Oh,please,sit.
您喝茶還是咖啡 康納斯夫人
Can I get you a cup of tea,or coffee,Mrs. Connors
不 不用了 謝謝
No,no thank you.
叫我伊芙就行
And please,call me Eve.
那麼
So...
我能幫你些什麼呢 伊芙
...what can I help you with,Eve
是這樣的 貌似我女兒凱特和你兒子正在約會
Well,it seems my daughter Kat and your son are dating.
嗯 我知道 下周他們要去一個大型盛裝舞會
Yeah,I know. They're going to some big fancy dance next week.
叫"秋之降臨"   對 就是這個
Fall formal.   Ah,the... that's... that's it.
菲爾 他非常激動
Phil is,he's so excited.
我覺得這可能是個讓你我親近的好機會
I thought it might be a good idea for us to get acquainted,
所以 我想自我介紹一下 我
so I wanted to introduce myself,and...
哇哦
Whoa. Whoops.
菲爾
Phil
抱歉 我不知道有客人
Sorry,I didn't know anyone was here.
菲爾 這是凱特的媽媽 康納斯夫人
Phil,this is Kat's mother,Mrs. Connors.
嘿
Hey.
她來跟咱們打個照面
She just,uh,came by to say hello.
呃 好吧
Uh,okay.
那 我先回房間了
Well,I'm just gonna head to my room.
他是個棒小伙
He's a nice boy.
你可以放心 伊芙 我家菲爾
You can rest assured,Eve,that my Phil
會好好待您女兒的
will take good care of your daughter.
他借了一套燕尾服 還有其他什麼的
He's rented a tux,and everything.
嗯
Yes.
下午我要帶凱特去商場買條新裙子
I'm taking Kat to the mall this afternoon to buy a new dress.
如果你媽媽那麼不開心
if your mother was so unhappy,
你覺得她最初為什麼嫁給你爸爸
why do you think she married your father in the first place
天啊 這我可不知道
God,I have no idea.
因為他是真命天子
Because he was there
我是說 他想娶她
I mean,he wanted to marry her.
可能她別無選擇
She had no other choice,maybe
我是說 她去大學做接待員
I mean,she went to college,and she was working as a receptionist,
但她還能做些什麼呢
but what else was she gonna do
我猜和我爸爸一起的生活
I guess life with my father
是非常冰冷而悲傷的
must have been pretty bleak and miserable for her.
那晚她離去前
In the weeks before she left
我注意到她的打扮有了變化
I noticed that she started dressing different.
變化是什麼意思
What do you mean,different
好比說 她的衣服更緊身 更性感了
Like,her clothes got tighter. Sexier.
她甚至買了一條迷你裙
I mean,she even bought a miniskirt.
也就是那晚她撞見我和菲爾
Then there was that night that she walked in on me and Phil.
我覺得菲爾該回家了
I think it's time for Phil to go home.
什麼 為什麼   時候不早了
What Why   It's late.
現在才11點多
It's not even midnight.
凱特 照我說的做 我說了你該睡覺了
Kat,what I say goes. And I say go to bed.
最古怪的是 她那件睡衣
The weirdest part was that she had on this nightgown
幾乎是透明的
that was practically see through.
就像一個走秀台的模特
It was almost like she was putting on a show.
難道這就是她在做的
Could it be that's what she was doing
啥 走秀
What Putting on a show
秀給我看 還是秀給菲爾看啊
For me,or for Phil
不是的
No.
我覺得她只是空虛寂寞
I think she was just bored.
更年期到了 想盡她所能吸引眼球
And getting older,and trying to get whatever attention she could.
簡直就像她要去約會一樣
It was almost like she wanted to have an affair or something.
你認為她要去約會
Do you think that's what was going on
不 我的意思 難以想像這種事情
No. I mean,I can't imagine it.
但一切皆有可能 不是嗎
But,I guess anything's possible,right
噢 抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
我敲了門 但沒人應
I tried knocking but there was no answer.
沒關係 有什麼要幫忙的嗎
That's all right. Could I help you with something
我在找我媽那隻大笨貓
I'm just looking for my mom's stupid cat.
你看到它了嗎
Have you seen him
沒看到
Can't say that I have.
好吧 抱歉打擾您了 康納斯夫人
Oh. Okay. Sorry to bother you,Mrs. Connors.
康納斯夫人聽起來太見外了 叫我伊芙就行
Mrs. Connors sounds so formal. Call me Eve.
哦 好吧
Oh. All right.
你知道我 跟你們這些年輕人比起來並不顯老
You know,the time when I was your age doesn't seem so far away to me.
我該繼續找我媽的貓了
Well,I should probably look for my mom's cat.
菲爾 今晚跟我們共進晚餐怎麼樣
Phil,would you like to have dinner with us tonight
我做了陽澄湖大閘蟹
I'm making crab thermador.
呃 行
Uh,sure.
7點鐘開飯
Dinner is at seven.
酷 謝謝 康納斯夫人 不對
Cool. Thanks,Mrs. Connor. I mean...
伊芙
...Eve.
你好 我是西奧·史澤警官
Uh,yeah,you've reached Detective Theo Scieziesciez.
請在嗶一聲後留言
Leave a message after the beep.
嗨 呃 警官 是我 凱特·康納斯
Hi. Um,Detective. It's,uh,it's Kat Connors.
我打給你 是因為我
I'm just... I'm just calling because I think
有一些關於
I might have some information
我媽媽的線索 呃
about my mother. Uh...
嗨 很高興又在這見到你了
Hey. Thanks again for meeting me here.
難以忍受節假日
Couldn't bear the thought of going
去辦公室的感覺 懂吧
into the office on my day off,you know
沒關係
No problem.
進來吧
Come on in.
謝謝
Thank you.
陋室 但總歸是家
It ain't fancy,but it's home.
要喝點什麼嗎   嗯 好啊
Can I get you a drink   Yeah,sure.
本想給你啤酒 不過你還未成年吧
I'd offer you a beer,but you're not of age.
給我一瓶吧
I'd take one anyway.
那好吧
All right then.
隨便坐
Sit down.
喝吧   謝謝
Go on.   Thanks.
那麼 有什麼要和我討論的嗎
So What do you want to talk to me about
我
I,um...
我打你電話是因為 我有一些新的發現
I... I called because I have some new information.
我記起一些事情 我覺得
I just remembered some things,and,
我媽可能有外遇
I think my mother may have been having an affair.
是嗎
Oh,yeah
這應該可以解釋她為什麼會失蹤 是嗎
I mean,it could explain why she left,right
也許吧 我週一會做調查
Maybe. I'll look into it on Monday.
好吧
Okay.
就這些
Is that it
我覺得這很可能和案情有關
I just thought that it might be,like,relative to the case.
你很緊張嗎
Are you nervous
我覺得有一點點吧
I guess. A little.
你想走隨時可以走的 知道嗎
Well,you know you can leave any time you want,right
我知道
I know.
但你還不想走 是不是
But,uh,you don't want to leave,do you.
你就是來勾引我的
Because you came here to seduce me.
祝賀你 妹子 你勾引成功了
Well,congratulations,sweetheart. It worked.
我被你誘惑到了
I'm seduced.
你幾歲了
And how old are you
18歲
Eighteen.
你不是處女了吧
You're not a virgin,are you
不是
No.
那麼
So,uh...
你知道接下來會發生什麼吧
...you know what's about to happen,right
你確定這是你想要的
And are you sure that's what you want
你知道 我不同於貴校任何一個朋克同學嗎
Because I'm not one of your punk classmates from school,you know
我知道
I know.
好吧 你身材很火辣 這是顯而易見的
Well,you're hot,that's for sure.
你的胸部相當完美
Your tits are perfect.
你自己心知肚明 不是嗎
But you already know that,don't you.
也許我應該和你坐近一點
Maybe I should come over there and join you.
嗯
Yeah.
這樣舒服些了
This better
嗯
Mm hm.
你為什麼不脫掉衣服
Why don't you take this top off,huh
很迷人
Fucking amazing.
想要嗎
Is this what you want
想
Yeah.
嘿   怎麼啦
Hey.   What
你沒事吧
Everything all right
沒事 我只是睡不著
Yeah. I just don't sleep so good sometime.
想到了很多糟糕的事情
I've seen a lot of bad shit.
那些死去的人
Dead people.
讓我很不安
Very unhappy about it.
哦 是嗎
Oh yeah
嗯
Yeah.
相信我 都是些可怕的事情
Trust me,you don't wanna know.
說來聽聽
Try me.
好吧
All right.
以前 這兒有個胖子
Once there was this obese man,
一群變態往他身上澆滿汽油
some sick fuck had doused him with gasoline
把他活活燒死
and lit him on fire.
兩天後 我們找到
And by the time we got to the body,
他的屍體
two days later,
屍體還在燃燒
he was still burning.
怎麼會這樣
What
他身上太多脂肪了
Guy had so much body fat,
被燒得像一尊人形蠟像一樣
he was like a human candle.
在我多年的警察生涯中
And there's one thing I've learned,
我長知識
in all my years as a cop,
一個人有可能會對另一個人 做喪心病狂
it's that people are capable of doing horrible,
喪盡天良的壞事
unimaginable things to each other.
喜歡你是如此的狡猾
Love how slippery you are.
感覺我好像會把你折成兩半
Feel like I could break you in half.
我其實還能更厲害的
I'm tougher than I look.
哦 是嗎   哦 是的
Oh,yeah   Oh,yeah.
那再來   好啊
Wanna try me   Yes.
哦 天啊
Oh,my God.
這有什麼 小事一樁
What It was easy.
這還算小事
What do you mean it was easy
不就是去和他做愛嗎
I mean I went over there and I fucked him.
哇 我對你刮目相看
Wow. I'm impressed.
完全被你打敗了 激情四射嗎
Truly,truly impressed. So was it hot
當然 他比菲爾強太多了
Oh,hell yes. Like,so much better than Phil.
真是個騷貨
Deets,girl,deets.
他真是男人中的極品
He's just,like,so manly.
器大活好 胸毛濃密 肌肉發達
Like,cock,and balls,and,like,hairy chest,and muscles,and,
還有啊 他身上散發的男子氣息
like,the way he smells,Beth,
那麼野性 那麼原始
is so intense. It's,like,primal.
哦 我現在還能聞到那氣息
Oh,I can still smell him on me now.
快讓我聞聞
Oh,my God,let me smell..
哦 天啊 這味兒老騷了
Oh,God,that's so hot.
我也好想有一天能好爽
One day I hope some musky macho stud
能睡一個肌肉男
will fuck the shit out of me too.
很快就會有的   是嗎 什麼時候 什麼時候
Oh,it'll happen.   Oh,yeah. When When
我真是羨慕嫉妒恨啊
I'm so proud of you.
幹嘛 就因為我睡了個老男人
Why Because I fucked an old guy
是啊
Yeah.
我是說 你不該走這條錯路的 凱特
I mean,don't take this the wrong way,Kat,
在很長一段時間內
but for the longest time
你都活在自己的世界裏
you were acting like you were still fat.
不好意思 我不知道你在說什麼
Oh my God. What are you talking about
你這樣會失去生活的重心的
I mean,you lost all of that weight,like,
你忘記了 大概三年前
what,three years ago
你對週遭世界那麼的恐懼和焦慮
But you're still skulking around all angsty and awkward.
跟我一樣像個肥婆
Like a fat chick. Like me.
還有米奇 他外表像瘦彎男其實內心是個肥直婆
And Mickey,who's basically a fat chick in a skinny gay body.
你這不扯麼   是大實話
You're crazy.   It's true.
康納你好
Mr. Connor,
我是羅馬琳達警局的雪莉警官
this is Sheryl from the Lorna Linda Police Department.
我們很高興地通知你 你通過了測謊試驗
I'm pleased to inform you that you passed your lie detector test.
謝謝你的合作 祝您生活愉快
Thank you for your cooperation,and have a nice day.
你爸幹嘛要去做測謊試驗
Why would your dad need to take a lie detector test
我不知道
I have no idea.
會不會條子覺得你爸知道些什麼
Well,do you think the cops think he knows something
我爸 貝絲 你又不是不認識他
My dad Beth,have you met him
你去字典裏找"燒餅"這個詞 我爸的照片就是註解
Look up clueless in the dictionary and there's a picture of him.
一定是條子查案方式不對
Must be some kind of mistake.
可能吧
Probably.
應該是他的車 你直接去問他吧
I think that's his car. Just ask him.
你趕我走啊   什麼 沒有 說什麼呢
Do you want me to leave   What No. Whatever.
我開玩笑的
I'm sure it's nothing.
嗨 親愛的 貝絲
Hi,sweetheart,Beth.
兩位大美人 在超市沒花太多錢吧
Kids didn't spend too much money at the mall,I hope
沒有 只買了一點點東西
Nope. I just picked up a few things.
爸爸 剛才有條
Hey,dad,there was a,uh,message for you,
電話留言 是警局打來的
on the machine,from the police department.
是關於媽媽的消息嗎
Is there news about your mother
不是 他們說你通過了測謊試驗
No. They said that you passed the lie detector test
哦 甚妙
Oh. Well,whoop dee do.
那貝絲留下一塊吃飯吧
So,you going to join us for dinner,Beth
不了 我得回去了 康叔
I... I don't think so,Mr. Connors.
嗯
Hm.
爸 警察為什麼讓你去測謊
Dad,why would they want you to take a lie detector test
我也不知道 大概是查案標準程序吧
Beats me. It's standard procedure in cases like this,I guess.
晚飯怎麼說 親愛的
So what are you feeling,sweetheart
要不還是叫外賣吧
Should we order takeout from that rib place
嗯 行啊
Yeah,sure.
媽媽
Mom
怎麼了 有什麼事嗎
What is it What's going on
菲爾的功夫不錯
Is Phil a good fuck
好去睡了 媽媽
Go to bed,mom.
不准背對著我
Don't you turn your back on me
我說真的 你趕緊回去睡覺吧
Seriously,just go back to bed.
別給臉不要臉
I will not be dismissed by the likes of you.
回答我   哎喲
Answer me   Ow
菲爾的床功很好嗎
Is Phil a good fuck
什麼玩意兒床功 你到底想問什麼
What would you know about fucking,anyway
幹嘛啊你
Oh my... what are you doing
這算什麼
What is this
媽媽 你要幹嘛   你為什麼不穿衣服
Mom,what are you...   Why are you naked
我熱啊 真是的 你出去
I was hot Jesus Get out of my room
你為什麼要這樣
Why are you doing this
我做錯什麼了我 住手
What did I ever do to you Stop
我太知道了
I do too know what a good fuck is.
你個小賤人
You little slut.
有病啊你
What is your problem
吃錯藥啦 你神經病沒好轉
Are you insane What is fucking wrong with you
哪個當媽的會對女兒做這種事
What kind of mother would do something like that
我媽
My mother.
怎麼了 幹嘛 她就是那樣對我的
What What That's just how she was.
每個人都有童年陰影
I mean,everyone has a crappy childhood.
但她這種和打罵體罰不一樣
It's not like she beat me.
所以我媽媽並不是完美無缺的模範母親
So my mom wasn't Hallmark Card perfect.
你有什麼好驚訝的
So fucking what
我覺得她很孤獨
I just think she was lonely.
有好幾次我發現她死盯著我的衣服看
I used to catch her staring at me,
搞得好像衣服是我從她那偷來的一樣
like I was wearing something that I had stolen from her.
很像當年的我
You look like I looked when I was you.
什麼
What
我是說 我當年和你現在一樣
I mean,you look like I looked when I was your age.
隨便你怎麼說 偷窺狂
Whatever,lurker.
幹嘛 你要幹嘛
What What do you want
沒什麼
Nothing.
哦 天啊 別盯著我看了 你的眼神太嚇人
Oh my God,stop gawking at me. You're creeping me out.
你走開 離我遠點
Just,like,get out of here. Just leave me alone.
大概一周前 她突然失蹤了
About a week before she disappeared,
那時我和菲爾在地下室做作業
Phil and I were in the basement doing homework,
就跟平常的夜晚一樣
just like any other ordinary night.
怎樣 覺得如何 你喜歡嗎
Well,what do you think You like
42歲依然風韻猶存 嗯哼
Pretty sexy for 42,huh
媽媽 你在幹什麼
Mom,what are you doing
哦 別緊張 一本正經小姐
Oh,loosen up,Miss Prissypants.
菲爾 你和你媽來我家一塊吃晚飯吧
Phil. Why don't you and your mother join us for dinner
我在做世界上最好吃的惠靈頓牛肉
I'm making my world famous Beef Wellington.
呃 好啊 康夫人 我會問我媽的
Uh,yeah,o... okay,Mrs. Connors. I'll ask.
甚妙
Splendid.
我打算狂慶祝
I'm in the mood for celebrating.
好了 媽 我們知道了 行了吧
Okay,mom,whatever. We get it already.
哦 怎麼了 凱特
Oh,what's the matter,Kat
難道你不能忍受媽媽的愛好略有改變
Can't stand seeing your mother have a little fun for a change
寶貝 我回來了
Honey,I'm home
哦 派對剛剛開始就結束了
Oh,and the party is over before it's even begun.
親愛的 你在哪
Sweetheart,where are you
你們在這啊 晚餐吃啥
There you are. What's for dinner
怎麼回事 你怎麼穿這個鳥樣
What's going on Why are you dressed like that
咋了 你不喜歡這樣
What You don't like it
沒說不喜歡
No. I don't.
瞧 緊身的 你不喜歡這裙子
Well,tough shit. You don't like this skirt
伊芙 別搞了   我不管
Eve,stop it.   I don't care.
我不管你喜不喜歡 反正跟你沒有什麼關係
You don't like this skirt and I don't care.
我不管你喜不喜歡
You don't like this skirt and I don't...
把你的臭爪挪開
Get your goddamned hands off me
我想穿什麼就穿什麼 無論何時心中一樣親
I'll wear whatever the hell I want. Whenever I want to
你在做什麼
What are you doing
我他媽的人生 每一個他媽的夜晚
What I do every fucking night of my fucking life,
都在給你們做他媽的晚飯
making your fucking dinner.
哦 說什麼呢   哦 什麼臭味
Oh,Jesus   Oh,shit What reeks
那肉 都腐爛了
The meat. It's all rotten.
一定是冰櫃插頭鬆了
Must have come unplugged.
別愣在那 快把插頭插上
Don't just stand there,plug it back in
這味就跟他媽的死人味一樣
Smells like a fucking dead body in here
看樣子我們得出去搓一頓了
Well,looks like we're going out for dinner tonight.
想吃中餐不
Wanna get Chinese
不 我才不要吃中餐
No. I don't want fucking Chinese.
好吧 那你喜歡吃什麼 伊芙 你要什麼
Okay,then,what would make you happy,Evie What do you want
我不要
I don't want this.
我什麼也不要
I don't want any of it.
你 還有這房子
You,this house.
伊芙
Evie.
我只想要回以前的生活
I want my fucking life back.
別 親愛的 咱下館子去
Come on,sweetheart. Let's go to dinner.
都說了我不想吃飯
I don't want fucking dinner
為什麼就沒人聽我說話
Why won't anyone listen to me
所以說她就這麼突然 人間蒸發了
So out of the blue she was just,like,poof
1991年      春
差不多
Pretty much.
你之前說你媽走了 原來是這個意思
You told me your mom left,but not like that.
我們做室友差不多一年了 所以
Well,we've been roommates for almost a year,so.
但是你不想找到她麼
But don't you wonder where she is
我是說 她應該就在某個地方 是吧
I mean,she's gotta be somewhere,right
我不知道 這太奇怪了
I don't know,it's weird.
現在幾乎都不怎麼想她的事了
Hardly even think about her anymore.
你知道 這麼多的時間已經過去了
You know,it's,like,so much time has passed,
我已經習慣了
that kinda just gotten used to it.
估計下周回家休息一下
Guess going home next week for break
過去 那幽靈一直在我眼前驅之不去
has kinda resurrected the ghost from my past.
說到幽靈 你不會想去見
Speaking of ghosts,you're not gonna go see
你那屌絲前男友吧 叫什麼來著
that loser boyfriend of yours,what's his name,are you
你是說菲爾
You mean Phil
也許吧 怎麼說
Maybe. Why
你知道我是力挺奧利佛的
Well,you know I'm team Oliver.
我跟奧利佛才好了幾個月
We've only been dating for a couple of months.
所以啊 足夠瞭解到他熱火又聰明
So That's enough to know that he's hot,and smart,
新時代的有為青年 不像那個叫什麼來著
and actually has a future,unlike what's his name.
辛迪 你只見過菲爾一面 上次週末的時候
Cindy,you met Phil once,for a weekend.
是啊 我看一眼就鑒定完畢
Yeah,that was enough.
不管怎樣 以後有的煩了
Whatever. The future bores me.
你還好嗎 沒啥事吧
What's going on with you tonight ls everything okay
很好啊 怎麼了
Yeah,why
不知道怎麼說 感覺你身在曹營心在漢
I don't know,you seem a million miles away.
不好意思 只是有一點心事
Sorry. Just a little preoccupied.
我沒事
I'm fine.
怎麼
What
沒怎麼
Nothing.
有話就說 別老說沒事
Don't say nothing when it's something.
好吧 你知道我不喜歡你抽煙
Okay,you know I don't like it when you smoke.
有害健康 而且你還在吃毓婷
It's bad for you,especially since you're on the pill.
好吧 這根只是今天的第2根
Yeah,well,this is only my second one today.
我會為了你戒煙的
I'm cutting back,just for you.
不是為我 懂嗎 是為你的身體健康
Don't cut back for me. Okay It's your health we're talking about.
好吧 大夫
Okay,doctor.
你滿意了沒
Are you satisfied
只要你不犯傻 我就滿意
Not if you're gonna be mad.
為什麼我會犯傻 嗯
Why would I be mad Hm
就因為要你教我怎麼做人嗎
Just because you're telling me what to do
我在宿舍不能抽煙 因為辛迪說煙味難聞
I mean,I can't smoke in my room because Cindy says it stinks,
我在男朋友身邊也不能抽煙 因為他說抽煙不健康
and I can't smoke around you because you say it's unhealthy.
凱特 其實你應該沒有尼古丁上癮
Kat,it's not like you're addicted to nicotine.
你才抽了兩個月
You've been smoking for two months.
夠啦 不管怎樣 我想做什麼就做什麼
Okay,well,whatever. I just want to be free to do what I want.
好吧 你抽吧 抽吧
Okay,fine. Go ahead and smoke.
我不想吵架
I don't want to fight.
好了 我錯了 行不
Look,I'm sorry,okay
我只是 我只是想你開開心心
I just... I want you to be happy.
我回家了   等等 怎麼啦
I think I'm just gonna head home.   Wait. What
我要走了 我要去做作業
I'm going. I have studying to do.
凱特 好了啦 你這是 這是幹嘛 別走
Kat,come on. What are... what are you doing Just stay.
晚安 奧利佛
Goodnight,Oliver.
天啊 你到底怎地了 玩真的
Oh my God,what is the matter with you Seriously
我做錯什麼了 凱特 凱特
What did I do Kat Kat
嘿 嗨 老爸
Hey Hi,dad.
哇
Wow.
怎麼了
What
真不敢相信 我女兒這麼漂亮了
I can't believe how grown up you look.
什麼呀 請你不要拍這種馬屁好嗎
Oh,God. Can we forego the theatrics,please
別嫌老爸肉麻 我想死我小乖乖了
Whatever. Act as jaded as you want,I missed my little girl
我想念你在心 口不難開
and I'm not ashamed to say so.
在伯克利大學讀得怎樣
So how is Berkeley
對了 謝謝你的信 老爸每封都看了
Thanks for all the letters,by the way.
哦 對不起 最近忙著看書忘了寫信
Oh,sorry. Been studying my ass off.
我明白 我明白
I know,I know.
你現在是混大城市的姑娘了
You're a big city girl now.
當然沒時間留給我這窮老爸
No time for your poor old dad.
歡迎你回家 親愛的
I'm glad you're home,sweetheart.
呃 我們是不是先
Uh,sh... should we
哦 對 你放著罷 我來拿
Yes. No,I got it. I got it. Ugh.
謝謝   走吧
Thank you.   Here.
這邊有啥子新聞或好玩的事
So,anything new and exciting around here
沒什麼 還是老樣子 沒啥大變化
Oh,not really. Much the same old,same old.
怎麼了
What
爸爸
Dad
爸爸 你怎麼了 好像有點心神不寧
Dad,what is it Why are you acting all weird
沒什麼 只是有那麼一件小事
Well,I do have a bit of news.
沒事吧
Is everything okay
沒啥大不了 只是 呃
Everything's fine. I just,um...
哦 天啊 別吞吞吐吐的
Oh my God,just spit it out already.
我 身邊多了一個人
I've been seeing someone.
真的啊   嗯 你不會生我氣吧
Really   Yes. Does it make you angry
怎麼會呢 開什麼玩笑
What Are you kidding me
沒事啦 爸爸 媽媽都不在這麼久了
No,dad,mom's been gone
你找其他女人這很正常啊
a long time. Why shouldn't you see other women
嗯 那好
Well,good.
那麼 她叫什麼名字
So,what's her name
梅   梅
May.   May
她是個推銷員 我在辦公室認識她的
She's a sales rep I met at the office.
爸爸 實在太好了
Dad,that's so great.
說心裏話 我真替你高興
Seriously,I'm really happy for you.
謝謝 寶貝 這對我而言很重要
Thank you,sweetheart. That means a lot to me.
那你準備在家幹些什麼
So,what are your plans while you're at home
呃 有些課題要研究一下
Uh,I have some studying to do,
不過 最主要我想歇歇
but mostly I just wanna relax,
去看看老朋友們 你認識的 以前那幾個
see some old friends. You know,the usual.
哇哦 稀客來了 歡迎
Wow. Welcome back,stranger.
好你個拋棄死黨的學霸
Such a fucking rebel.
凱特 你是我的新偶像
Kat,you're my new idol.
天啊 我想死你們了
Oh,my God,I've missed you guys.
我是說 我在伯克利的朋友都很好
I mean,my friends at Berkley are nice and everything,
就是有點無聊
but just kind of boring.
哦 我也好想你啊
Oh,I missed you too.
這鳥不拉屎的鄉下地方 我都呆膩了
What I haven't missed is this shitty little pisshole of a town.
哦 剛才早上 我老媽還叫我把屋子收拾乾淨
Oh my God,my mom told me to clean my room this morning.
我真想錘死她
I almost bludgeoned her to death.
呃 真難想像我們曾在這生活
Ugh,I can't believe we ever lived here.
我懂
Oh,I know.
不過有一點比較安逸 這小鎮一直沒變
Though I kind of find it reassuring that this place never changes.
懂我意思嗎 就好像時間被凍結了一樣
You know It's like it's frozen in time.
你覺得你變了
And you think you've changed
啊 是 我是這麼說過
Oh,yeah. I'd say so.
我是說 以自己的本來面目生活更好過些
I mean,I definitely feel more comfortable in my own skin.
在學校都還好吧   嗯
School's going well   Mm hm.
你還是沒你媽媽的消息
And I assume you haven't heard from your mother.
沒 杳無音訊
Nope. Not a word.
你有什麼感受嗎 這都已經兩年了
How are you feeling about that It's been over two years.
我 我不知道
I... I don't know.
這 這麼說吧 我已經不抱什麼希望了
It's... it's kind of gotten to the point where
我已經對這事失去信心了
I just don't even expect to hear from her anymore.
我就是習慣了這種詭異的現狀
I've just come to this weird sort of acceptance of it.
我覺得我可能才剛開始習慣
Guess I've just moved on.
我是說 甚至連我爸都給自己找了個新女友
I mean,even my dad has himself a new girlfriend.
這件事令你不安嗎
Does that bother you at all
沒有啊 為什麼這麼問
Hm mm. Why should it
我媽走了 不可能再回來了
My mother's gone. She's never coming back.
嗨
Hey.
最近怎樣 你氣色不錯啊
How're you doing You look great.
謝謝 你也一樣
Thank you. You too.
嗨 亞倫 我可以抽會兒煙嗎
Hey,Aaron,okay if I grab a smoke break
快點 我們他媽有一大堆事兒要做
Make it quick. We got a fuckload of work to do.
走吧
Come on.
在學校還算好
So school's going good
還好 你呢 你過得咋樣
It's all right. How about you How've you been
你知道的 除了幹活就是照顧老媽
You know,work,taking care of my mom.
還是老一套
Same old,same old.
她還好吧   我媽
How is she   My mom
嗯
Yeah.
還是瘋婆子一個
Batshit crazy as ever.
給我一根唄
Can I have one
好啊 你也抽煙了
Sure. You're smoking now
偶爾吧 謝了
Sometimes. Thanks.
啥時候回來的
When'd you get back into town
呃 就幾天前
Um,couple of days ago.
對不起 我我應該早點打電話給你的
I'm sorry,I... I would have called sooner.
這兩天實在太忙 所以
Just been really busy,and...
沒關係 回來就好
Whatever. It's cool.
趁我這幾天在 咱們應該出去走走的
But,uh,we should,we should hang out while I'm here.
看看電影什麼的
Catch a movie or something
行啊 那敢情好
Yeah. Sounds good.
我這週四走
Here 'til Thursday.
很好啊
Cool.
你其實沒必要的 你懂嗎
You don't have to,you know.
沒必要什麼
Have to what
看我
See me.
我是說 你不用浪費寶貴時間來看我這種渣渣
I mean,I know you might not have time for an asshole like me,
你可是名牌大學高材生
now that you're a hot shit college student.
菲爾 你說什麼呢
Phil,what are you talking about
我當然想見你
Of course I want to see you.
嗯 好吧
Right,whatever.
我得回去幹活了 我老闆脾氣大得很
I better get back to work before my boss has a cow.
好
Yeah.
很抱歉我來晚了 路上堵的不成樣子
I am so sorry that I'm late. Traffic was ridiculous.
沒關係 寶貝
No problem,sweetheart.
凱特 這是梅阿姨 梅 這是凱特
Kat,this is May. May,Kat.
很高興我們有這樣一個機會見面
I'm so happy we finally get the chance to meet.
我之前有聽過關於你的很多事
I've heard so much about you.
噢 我也是 呵呵
Oh,me too.hehe
你真人比你爸描述的更可愛
And you're even lovelier than your father described.
噢 沒這麼誇張吧
Oh. I'm sure that's not true,
不過還是謝謝誇獎
but thank you anyway.
這次回家要休息幾天 凱特麗娜
So how long will you be in town,Katrina
哦 就一周而已 然後就回學校
Oh,just a week. Then it's back to the salt mines.
凱特第一學期成績可是全優哦
Kat got almost all "A"s her first semester.
哇哦 恭喜恭喜
Wow,congratulations.
是啊 很走運 你們點菜了沒 我快餓死了
Yeah. I lucked out. Have you guys ordered yet I'm starved.
你的最愛 菠菜洋薊開胃菜
Your favorite,the spinach artichoke appetizer.
已經在做了   哦 太好了
It's already on its way.   Oh,yes.
我得去趟洗手間
I'm going to make a quick trip to the ladies room.
等會服務員來了 你知道我要點什麼的
If the waiter comes,you know what I want.
好 去吧
Right,okay.
那麼 你覺得怎樣
So,uh,are you all right with this
什麼 你說梅阿姨嗎
What You mean May
好吧 爸爸 我喜歡她 她看上去挺親切的
Yeah,Dad I like her. She seems sweet.
我不想讓你感到尷尬
I just don't want it to be awkward for you.
爸爸 我跟你說過了 你找新女友我很高興
Dad,I told you I am thrilled that you met someone.
說真的 你理應得到幸福
Seriously,you deserve to be happy.
摘下婚戒吧
Took off your wedding ring.
這東西會讓梅不好受
It makes May uncomfortable.
我是在她不在的時候重新戴上的
I put it back on when she's not around.
何必如此 是媽媽拋棄了我們
Why bother I mean,mom left us.
是她自己作出的選擇 我已經接受這點了
She's the one who made that choice. I accept that now.
是時候開始我們的新生活了
It's about time we get on with our lives.
媽媽
Mom
凱特
Kat.
怎麼了 出什麼事了
What is it What's wrong
我把手放進水裏 結果手不見了
I put my hands in the water,and they disappeared.
什麼
What
我在洗碗 這水太涼了
I was doing the dishes and the water was so cold.
水槽底下有個勺子
There was a spoon at the bottom of the sink,
當我把手從水裏拿出來時
and when I lifted my hands out of the water...
怎麼了
What's the matter
呃 沒啥
Um,nothing.
有時會做奇怪的夢
Just have strange dreams sometimes.
是麼
Oh yeah
是的
Yeah.
自從我媽失蹤後開始做那種怪夢
They started after my mother disappeared.
以前一直做
Used to get them all the time.
最近幾周來還是第一次
It's actually the first one I've had in weeks.
很少聽你談起你母親
You hardly ever talk about your mother.
沒什麼好談的 她都走了
There's not much to say. She's gone.
那個心理醫生說夢是毫無意義的
The shrink says dreams are meaningless.
我不敢茍同
I don't think I agree with that.
我做的這些夢 你怎麼看
What do you think my dreams mean
你真的想知道
You really want my opinion
當然了 你說嘛
Of course. Why wouldn't I
你知道 我們盡全力仔細找過你的母親
As you know,we did an exhaustive search for your mother.
仔細 你們連灰都找不到
Exhaustive You guys barely even looked for her.
實際上 我們做了一個徹底的調查
Actually,a very thorough investigation was done.
為了找你母親 我們花了超過兩年的時間
We spent over two years looking for your mom.
但一點線索都沒有
Not a single trace was ever found.
嗯哼 無所謂了
Mm hm. Whatever.
你覺得她現在在哪兒
So where do you think she is
我覺得她死了
I think she's dead.
什麼
What
上次你跟我說她有外遇
Well,you said yourself she was having an affair,
這點我們證實了
which we confirmed.
還有你的鄰居也這麼說 好像是叫布朗曼夫人
With your neighbor,Mrs. Blangman
是希爾曼夫人
Mrs. Hillman.
反正就是她 說你母親搞了個小三
Whatever. She said your mom had a boyfriend.
她怎麼知道的
How would she know
她很八卦
She's nosy.
她是個瞎子
She can't see.
等一下 就算我媽搞小三
Wait... whatever. Even if my mom did have a boyfriend,
那也不至於跑到一個
doesn't it just make it that much more likely
誰也找不到的地方吧
that she just ran off somewhere
怎麼了
What
怎麼了 說話啊 你怎麼不說話了
What What is it What aren't you saying
我們對你父親的背景做了一個全面調查
We did a thorough background check on your father.
一些被調查者告知我們
Several interviewees told us
你父親是一個暴力且易妒的人
that he was a pretty jealous and volatile man.
我爸就是一個膽小鬼
My dad is a fucking wimp.
所以他才會常常令我媽感到厭煩
That's why he used to drive my mom crazy.
這跟鮑勃·卡爾森和瑪吉·卡爾森的描述不符
Not according to Bob and Margie Carlsen.
這倆貨又是誰   你家以前的鄰居
Who are they   Your former neighbors.
住在河畔 你父母曾住在他們家隔壁
Your parents used to live next door to them in Riverside.
他們向我們透露 你父親總是懷疑你母親
They told us that when your father suspected your mother
與鮑勃·卡爾森有染
had a thing for Bob Carlsen,
所以他點燃了一個垃圾桶
he lit a trash can on fire
扔到卡爾森家的後院裏
and he tossed it onto their patio.
瞎說
That's ridiculous.
從來沒聽說過有這號人 再說那是二十年前的事了
Never even heard of these people,and that was two decades ago.
好吧 就算我爸真的那麼危險
Fine,if my dad was so dangerous,
你們幹嘛不逮捕他
then why didn't you ever arrest him
沒有證據
No evidence.
我們甚至找不出足夠理由申請搜查證
We didn't even have sufficient cause for a search warrant.
如果你想聽聽我的專業推理 我會告訴你
Asked for my professional opinion,and I told you.
凱特 我是這麼想的
Kat,that's just what I think.
你說
Which is
我認為你母親和小三被你父親捉姦在床
I think you father caught your mother
你父親殺了她
fucking her boyfriend and he killed her.
那他怎麼處理屍體
Well,then what did he do with the body
那就是一個未解之謎了
That's a damn mystery.
凱特 拜託
Kat. Come on.
你要去哪兒
Where are you going
警官 你知道我怎麼想的嗎
You know what I think,Detective
你真的是名副其實的狗屁警官
I think you're full of shit.
再來啊 猛男 你可以做得更好的
Come on,strong man. You can do better than that.
怎麼弄 就像這樣
What,like this
不 用點力
No. Harder.
好好用用這身肌肉 這就對了
Put those muscles to good use for a change. That's better.
就是這樣 繼續 來個重拳
That's it. Come on,give it a whack.
你已經到了
You're already here
呃 是啊 我在幫你媽媽做飯呢
Uh,yeah. I was just helping your mom with dinner.
不像某些人
Unlike some people.
嗨 希夫人 是我 凱特 不好意思 你休息了嗎
Hi,Mrs. Hillman. It's Kat. I'm sorry,were you in bed
哦 沒 我 我剛躺下
Oh,oh no. I... I was just lying down.
我 我身體感覺不太好
I... I haven't been feeling well.
哦 很抱歉打擾您 呃 菲爾在麼
Oh. Well,I'm sorry to bother you. But,uh,is Phil here
不 他不在
No. He isn't.
那您知道他在哪兒嗎   不清楚啊
Do you know where he is   I'm afraid not.
這小子有時候喜歡出去閒逛
That boy sometimes goes out gallivanting
玩到很晚才回來
'til all hours of the night.
好吧 他回來的時候叫他給我打個電話好嗎
Okay,well,could you please tell him to call me as soon as he gets home
我有要緊事找他   嗯 我知道了
It's kind of important.   Uh... of course.
謝謝 再次抱歉打攪您休息
Thank you. Sorry again for bothering you.
哦 沒沒什麼 晚安 親愛的
Oh,it's... it's no problem. Goodnight,dear.
晚安
Good night.
我覺得這不合適吧
I don't think it's right with her here.
但是如果凱特說她沒問題的話
But if Kat says she's comfortable,I don't...
關鍵不是凱特怎麼說
I don't care what Kat said.
爸爸
Dad
寶貝 噢 對不起
Honey Aww,I'm sorry.
我沒想吵醒你
I didn't mean to wake you.
你是不是在跟梅阿姨爭論她能否在這過夜
If you two are arguing over whether or not
我反正沒意見的
May can sleep over,it's totally fine.
寶貝 我覺得吧
Sweetheart,I don't think...
不 不 爸爸 真的沒關係 我不介意
No,no,no,dad,seriously. I don't mind.
你太累了 明天還得送你去機場
Well,you're sick,and we have to get you to the airport tomorrow.
我好多了 而且我的航班是下午的
I'm almost better. My flight's not until the afternoon.
總之我是一家之主 這裏我說了算
You know what,this is my house and I call the shots around here.
抱歉 凱特
Sorry,Kat.
我不是故意把你牽扯進來
I didn't mean for you to get dragged into this.
敬菲爾 祝他死無全屍
To Phil,may he rest in pieces.
哦 天啊
Oh,my God,
不 去幹菲爾 干他
No,fuck Phil. Seriously,fuck him.
那蠢貨都沒回我電話
The jerk never even called me back.
客觀 去幹菲爾
That's the spirit. Fuck Phil.
或者 反一反 不干他了 不干菲爾了
Or,rather,don't fuck Phil. Stop fucking Phil.
對 嗷
Yeah. Oh
不如操那個風騷的條子
Fuck that hot stud cop instead.
一次又一次
Done and done.
你們知道嗎 他前天晚上說了些怪話
You know,he said something kind of weird the other night.
他說什麼了
What'd he say
"我要幹得你兩腳發軟"
"I'm gonna plow you 'til you can't walk straight"
沒有 呃 他說
No. Um,yeah,it was so...
他說他覺得我爸殺了我媽
He said that he thinks my dad killed my mother.
怎麼說
What
說話呀
我 我幾年前跟你說過的 凱特
I... I told you that,Kat. Ages ago.
我們都跟你說過
We both did.
你倆說啥呢
What are you talking about
那時候你媽媽剛失蹤
It was right after your mom disappeared,
你好像不樂意聽那些
and you just didn't seem to want to hear it.
記得嗎 我懷疑你老爸是不是在隱瞞什麼
Remember I asked if maybe your dad had something to hide
你否決了
You just blew it off.
你說他那麼透明 怎麼會藏得住什麼
You said he was too transparent to hide anything.
你倆瘋了
You guys are fucking crazy.
好吧 當我們沒說
Yeah. Forget it.
我倆看了太多懸疑片
We both watch way too much bad TV.
但這也是我們仨在一起的原因 不是嗎
But that's why you love us,right
呃 天啊
Ugh. God,
再沒有比又熱又不夠勁的香檳更噁心了
there's nothing more disgusting than warm,flat champagne.
把那個給我   什麼
Here,give me that.   What
瓶子 謝謝
The bottle,please.
你要幹嘛
What are you doing
這是個學校裏學的把戲
It's a trick I learned at school.
把瓶子放在冰櫃幾分鐘
You put the bottle in the freezer for a few minutes,
它就冰得完美了 過來幫我
and it is chilled to perfection. Come and help me.
米奇   讓我去搬那些舊到發霉的報紙
Mickey   There's no way that I am moving
甭想 門兒都沒有
a bunch of old,moldy newspapers. Fuck that.
你個皮包骨的基佬 快過來
Get your skinny gay ass over here.
呃
Unh.
拿走
Get that one.
卡住了
It's stuck.
怎麼回事
What the...
為什麼給一個冰櫃上鎖
Why would you lock a fucking freezer
你們在樓下搞什麼呢
What the hell is going on down here
沒什麼 我們在聊天 喝香檳
Nothing. We're just talking,and drinking champagne.
你朋友該走人了
Well,it's time for your friends to leave.
你說什麼
What are you talking about
你聽到了 凱特 我說 派對到此結束
You heard me,Kat. The party is over.
你開玩笑嗎
Are you joking
爸 不是我存心頂撞你 可我已經是成年人了
Dad,I hate to break it to you,but I'm a fuckin' adult.
你不能指揮我做什麼
You can't tell me what to do.
只要你在我的屋裏 就必須按我說的做
When you're under my roof,you will do as I say.
我說 你的朋友都回家去 馬上
And I'm saying your friends need to go home,now.
天啊 你犯什麼毛病
Oh my God. What is your problem
算了 凱特 沒關係的
Cool it. It's... it's okay,Kat.
沒錯 別著急   不是
Yeah. Don't worry about it.   No...
晚安 康納斯先生
Goodnight,Mr. Connors.
等等 我送你們
Wait,I'll walk you guys out.
謝謝你讓我在朋友面前徹底蒙羞
Thank you for completely humiliating me in front of my friends.
真他媽的高興 明天就能離開這鬼地方
So fucking glad I'm getting out of here tomorrow.
真抱歉 我爸這麼不給面子
Sorry my dad is being such a douche.
無所謂 反正我明天就飛走了
Whatever. I gotta fly out early tomorrow anyway.
我也是 我包裹還沒整理呢
Me too,and I'm not even packed yet.
你開車沒問題嗎
Sure you're okay to drive
我不像你們輕量級選手 我能住搞定酒精
Unlike you lightweights,I can handle my liquor.
天啊 我會想你們的
God,I'm gonna miss you guys.
哦 天啊 小題大做的人
Oh my God,drama queen.
很快就暑假了 到時我們還會回這個令人不爽的小窩
It'll be summer soon,and we'll be back in this rancid hellhole
待3個月的
for three freakin' months.
我知道
I know.
那好 保重 別忘了寫信
Yeah,well,take care. Don't forget to write.
會的 你也是 傻丫頭
Yeah. You too,shithead.
再見 凱特 路上小心 好嗎
Bye,Kat. Have a safe flight,all right
你們也是
You too.
嘿
Hey.
你還好嗎 你好像喝醉了
Are you all right You look drunk.
哦 是嗎 瞧瞧誰在說話呢
Oh,yeah Look who's talking.
你故意躲著我 還是什麼
So you've been avoiding me on purpose,or what
什麼意思   我上禮拜來你家
What do you mean   I came by your house last week.
跟你媽說過我想找你談談
Told your mother that I needed to talk to you.
是嗎 我不知道這事
Really I didn't get the message.
那你想和我談什麼
What did you want to talk to me about
談一些我一直在想的事情
Just been thinking about a lot of things.
我覺得我媽失蹤以後
You know,I feel like after my mother left,
我倆之間的一切都變了
everything changed between us.
我們變了 你變了
We were different. You were different.
那之後所有事都變了
Everything was different after that.
菲爾 那天你去哪了
Phil,where were you that day
你本應該來學校接我
You were supposed to pick me up from school.
我告訴過你 我在托馬斯那
I told you. I was at Thomas'.
天啊 你還沒明白嗎
My God,don't you get it
現在這個已經不重要了 你不必撒謊了
It doesn't matter anymore. You don't have to lie.
你什麼意思 你憑什麼說我撒謊
What do you mean What makes you think that I'm lying
好吧 我不是因為你撒謊指責你
Okay,I'm not accusing you of lying.
我現在的意思是 無論你知道什麼 請你告訴我
All I'm saying is whatever it is that you know,you can just tell me.
知道嗎 我們以前很開心 美好
You know what What we had was sweet,and cute,
一切都很好 但是你我都清楚我們兩個已經結束了
and great and everything,but I think we both know that it's over.
那些都已成過去
It's in the past,
我需要知道的是那天到底發生了什麼
and I need to know what happened that day
好讓我的新生活繼續下去
so that I can move on with my life.
求你了 菲爾 我不是在生你的氣
Please,Phil,I'm not gonna get mad at you.
我只是想知道真相
I just want to know.
我跟你說過 我什麼都不知道
I told you. I don't know anything.
你和我媽媽之間發生過什麼嗎
Was there something going on between you and my mother
什麼   別裝蒜了
What   You heard me.
你是不是和我媽上床了 我有證人能證明
Were you fucking my mom Because some people think that you were.
什麼 什麼玩意 什麼證人
What... what... what people
凱特 你 你喝多了 你發酒瘋了
Kat,you're... you're drunk. And crazy.
菲爾 我只是想知道真相
Phil,I just need to know
求你了 我不在乎真相是什麼
Please,I don't care what it is.
我受夠了活在這灰暗陰沉的日子裏
I just cannot keep living my life in the dark just,
我受夠了這稀里糊塗的人生
like,fucking wondering
我幫不了你 凱特
I can't help you,Kat.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但是我可以告訴你一件事
But I will tell you one thing.
你爸知道她在哪
Your dad knows where she is.
他一直都把她留在身邊
He's been keeping her up his sleeve this whole time.
你什麼意思
What do you mean
別問我 去問他
Don't ask me. Ask him.
凱特 凱特
Kat Kat
我在上面
I'm up here
這兒
Over here
不 這邊
No This way
對 正前方
Yes Right in front of you
我就在這 凱特
I'm right here,Kat.
救我
Help me
求你 救我 凱特
Please Help me,Kat
救我
Help me
百憂解
凱特
Kat
你在幹嗎
What are you doing
爸
Dad
你知道媽媽在哪嗎
Do you know where mom is
什麼
What
你知道媽媽在哪嗎
Do you know where mom is
菲爾說你知道
Because Phil says that you do.
菲爾 就那個工作都保不住的吸毒前男友
Phil Your stoner boyfriend who can't keep a job
答案是"不 我不知道"
The answer is no,I don't.
還有什麼事
Anything else
那好 把這些亂七八糟的收拾乾淨
Well,clean up this mess.
幾小時內要把你送到機場
We have to get you to the airport in a few hours.
爸爸
Dad
對不起
I'm sorry.
沒關係
It's all right.
記得打個電話 好讓爸爸知道你安全著陸
So make sure to call so I know that you landed all right.
好
Okay.
那幾個月後見了
So see you in a couple of months
嗯
Mm hm.
我愛你 寶貝
I love you,baby.
我也愛你
I love you too.
我該上飛機了
I should probably board.
再見
See you.
再見 寶貝
Goodbye,sweetheart.
那是我最後一次見我父親
That was the last time I saw my father.
事實證明貝絲 米奇和西奧是對的
It turns out Beth,Mickey and Theo were right.
我離開幾個星期後 爸爸在一個酒吧喝得爛醉如泥
A few weeks after I left,my dad got shitfaced drunk in a bar,
酒後吐真言 說出了殺死媽媽的真相
and confessed to killing my mother.
他用監獄裏的床單上吊自殺
He hung himself in his jail cell with a sheet.
在他死之前
Before he died,
他招認了媽媽的屍體在冰櫃裏
he revealed that my mother's body was in the freezer,
那天晚上趁我睡著的時候把屍體帶了出去
and that he'd taken it out during the night while I was sleeping.
他把屍體埋在山上 屍體被凍了很久
He buried her up in the mountains. Since it'd been frozen for so long,
因此腐爛得特別快
her corpse decomposed freakishly fast,
埋掉之後爛為液體
turning to liquid as it melted.
警察把屍體挖出來的時候 基本什麼都沒剩下了
By the time they dug her up,there was basically nothing left.
媽媽失蹤的時候我17歲
I was seventeen when my mother disappeared.
那天她在家打掃 做晚飯
Like,one day she was there,cleaning,making dinner,
第二天 她不見了
and the next... she was gone.
停下來
Stop it.
伊芙 別笑了
Evie,stop.
伊芙
Evie.
別笑了
Stop.
我求你了
Please.
伊芙
Evie.
別笑了
Stop
Stop.
我愛你
I love you.
因為我再沒見過媽媽
Because I never saw my mother again,
她對我來說是缺失的
she remains in absence to me.
一片空白
An empty space.
一個看不見 半記憶的幽魂
An invisible,half remembered ghost.
因為我再沒見過媽媽
So even now I catch myself thinking
某一天我會投入她的懷抱
that I'm gonna run into her some day.
就像我在紅燈前停下 打量旁邊的車
Like I'll be at a stop light,and look over at the car next to me
她會出現 並且不贊成的怒視我
and there she'll be,scowling at me with disapproval.
亦或是 我帶著她穿過擁擠的街道 或者火車站
Or I'll spot her across some crowded street,or train station,
我們朝著彼此跑過去 就像俗套的韓劇劇情一樣
and we'll run toward each other like one of those cheesy TV movies.
她會抱住我 像久別重逢的愛人
She'll hug me like a long,lost lover,
用她細長美妙的手
then take my face in her long,
撫摸我的臉
graceful hands,
盯著我的眼睛說
look me in the eyes and say...
"我在這 凱特"
..."I'm here,Kat.
"我就在這"
I'm here."